Dedicated Counselling Psychologist with strong educational background and practical experience in the field in providing therapeutic support to individuals navigating various mental health challenges. Proficient in employing evidence-based approaches such as cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT), mindfulness techniques, and Neuro-linguistic programming to facilitate positive change and personal growth. Strong communicator with a compassionate demeanor, committed to promoting mental well-being and facilitating the journey towards healing and selfdiscovery.

C

8447454806



Address: NPL, Kingsway Camp, New Delhi, Pin Code: 110009



akankshajeph03@gmail.com

Akanksha Jeph

COUNSELLING PSYCHOLOGIST

Skills

- Counselling
- · Skilled in Intake Interviewing
- Verbal and Written Communication Skills
- Time Management
- Creative Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Active Listening
- Positive psychology
- Group Counselling

Work Experience

Psychologist- Physio Karma, New Delhi November 2023- Present

- Provide counseling services in a government project at BM Gange School for students, addressing a wide range of emotional and behavioral issues through individual, group counseling sessions.
- Work with students with diverse needs, including but not limited to Autism Spectrum Disorder, Down Syndrome, Cerebral Palsy, Intellectual Disability, and ADHD within the Special Needs Wing of Airforce Golden Jubilee Institute (govt. project).
- Utilize brain training using neurofeedback and virtual reality to enhance the well-being and cognitive development of children in both educational settings.
- Collaborate with school staff and parents to create effective intervention plans and support systems for students.
- Developed educational content for their website, focusing on mental health awareness.
- conducted workshops for students and teachers.

Work Experience

Mental health counsellor- freelance December 2022- Present

- Conducted one-on-one counselling sessions with clients, fostering a safe and nonjudgmental environment for open dialogue and self-expression.
- Provided counseling and psychotherapy services to clients across various age groups, addressing a wide range of mental health concerns, including depression, anxiety, trauma, stress management, self esteem issues and relationship issues.
- Collaborated with clients to set achievable goals and monitor progress, continuously adapting strategies to meet evolving therapeutic needs.
- Guided clients in developing coping skills, resilience, and effective problem-solving techniques to enhance their overall emotional wellness.

Internship at The Talking Minds, New Delhi 3 months

- Consult and collaborate with instructors to develop treatment plans based on the patient's psychological problems.
- Evaluated patient's mental health through interviews, observations, and case histories.
- Provided therapies as per patient's needs and interests.
- Modified therapy plan based on patient's progress.
- Worked with other medical staff to coordinate patient care services.
- Explained patients and families about treatment procedures

Education History

1. B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Maharaja Surajmal Institute of Technology Graduated: 2020

2. MA in Psychology IGNOU 2023

3. Post Graduate Diploma in Guidance and Counselling Jamia Millia Islamia In Progress: 2023-2024